Richard Eldridge

SUMMARY:

Software Developer with 2 years full stack experience. Adept at back-end scripting and object-oriented programming from numerous API integrations and modernizing legacy programming. Additional knowledge and skills in e-commerce business operations, working with remote team members, professional communication and troubleshooting complex problems all refined from working under individuals with decades of experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Atlanta Network Technologies (ANTonline)

Smyrna, GA | Jun 2022 - current

Software Developer I

API Integration & Maintenance

Implemented new 3rd party integrations using PHP scripts with OOP and MVC architecture. This Reduced maintenance time by 50% compared to legacy integrations.

Update & Extend Infrastructure

- Created a Linux and PHP solution to ensure synchronous script function in an autonomous scheduled environment.
- Used Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) to unify front and back-end code to reduce code complexity and repetition for all logistic related views. This reduced maintenance time by over 80%.
- Designed and implemented an API that allowed JavaScript (JS) to utilize and call PHP classes and functions through the JS Fetch API.

Create Reports

- Developed a PHP and JavaScript report architecture that allowed reports to be reactive without refresh and reduced code required by 50%leveraging an API and class architecture I designed.
- This design greatly improved the user experience and allowed for a singlpoint of code truth which reduced bugs and required testing time.
- Modernized legacy reports to Model View Controller (MVC) and OOP architecture to decrease future maintenance time by 75% by improving code readability.
- Created scripts to upload and ingest CSV, XLXS files into Database.

Monitor & Report Logs

- Interpreted system logs to identify new customer facing bugs before they were reported thus saving PR and preserving customers.
- Proactively identified and resolved several critical errors, including checkout issues, before customers reported them.

SGPS ShowRig, Inc.

Norcross, GA | Feb. 2015 - Jun 2020

Department Head of Motor and Power Control

EDUCATION:

Software Development Diploma

*EU Accredited RQF Level 5 Diploma Code Institute May 2020 - Nov. 2021

Bachelor's of Computer Science Kennesaw State University

**In progress - Senior

CONTACT:

Richardaeld@gmail.com

GitHub

<u>LinkedIn</u>

SKILLS:

Languages

JavaScript

Java

PHP

CSS / HTML

Python

Tools

Linux

Git

Google Meets

Docker

Visual Studio Code

Databases

Percona

MySQL

PostgreSQL

Mongo DB

Libraries

Node.js

Express.js

React.js

API Integrations

Walmart

FedEx

Endicia

eBay

Amazon

Target

ACCOLADES: